<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pau Torras</title><link>https://ptorras.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Pau Torras</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Pau Torras</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 21:25:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ptorras.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://ptorras.github.io/resume/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 22:58:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ptorras.github.io/resume/</guid><description>I am a Computer Vision researcher interested in Document Analysis and Optical Music Recognition. I also have interests in other Computer Science-related technologies such as Compiler Construction or Language Processing.
I am currently looking for a Ph. D. Scholarship in order to dedicate myself to the development of intelligent music reading systems.
Publications Conferences P. Torras, A. Baró, L. Kang, and A. Fornés, “On the Integration of Language Models into Sequence to Sequence Architectures for Handwritten Music Recognition” in Proceedings of the 22nd International Society for Music Information Retrieval Conference, Online, Nov.</description></item><item><title>Inauguration</title><link>https://ptorras.github.io/posts/test/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 21:25:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ptorras.github.io/posts/test/</guid><description>I have finally decided to build my own blog. Not that I expect to be very active, nor to people to find my writing appealing in any way, shape or form. Nevertheless, I find it very interesting to have a place where I can lay out my thoughts and essentially scream into the endless void that is the Internet.
That&amp;rsquo;s pretty much it for the introductions. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested to know who I am, do head over to my about page.</description></item></channel></rss>