<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pau Torras</title><link>https://ptorras.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Pau Torras</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Pau Torras</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 22:58:56 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ptorras.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://ptorras.github.io/resume/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 22:58:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ptorras.github.io/resume/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am a Ph. D. student at the Computer Vision Center working in Document Analysis and
Optical Music Recognition. I also have interests in other Computer Science-related
technologies such as Compiler Construction or Language Processing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="publications">Publications&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="journals">Journals&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>P. Torras, S. Biswas and A. Fornés, &lt;strong>A unified representation framework for the evaluation of Optical Music Recognition systems&lt;/strong> in International Journal on Document Analysis and Recognition (IJDAR), Vol 27 No 3 pp. 379-393, 2024&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="conferences">Conferences&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>P. Torras, A. Baró, L. Kang, and A. Fornés, &lt;strong>“On the Integration of Language Models into Sequence to Sequence Architectures for Handwritten Music Recognition”&lt;/strong> in Proceedings of the 22nd International Society for Music Information Retrieval Conference, Online, Nov. 07, 2021, pp. 690–696. doi: 10.5281/zenodo.5624451.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="workshops">Workshops&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>P. Torras, M. A. Souibgui, J. Chen, and A. Fornés, &lt;strong>“A Transcription Is All You Need: Learning to Align Through Attention”&lt;/strong> in Document Analysis and Recognition – ICDAR 2021 Workshops, 2021, pp. 141–146. doi: 10.1007/978-3-030-86198-8_11.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>P. Torras, M. A. Souibgui, J. Chen, and A. Fornés, &lt;strong>&amp;ldquo;An Evaluation of Handwritten Text Recognition Methods for Historical Ciphered Manuscripts&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong> in Proceedings of the 7th International Workshop on Historical Document Imaging and Processing, 2023, pp. 7-12. doi:10.1145/3604951.3605509.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>P. Torras, M. A. Souibgui, J. Chen, S. Biswas, and A. Fornés, &lt;strong>&amp;ldquo;Segmentation-Free Alignment of Arbitrary Symbol Transcripts to Images&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong> in Document Analysis and Recognition – ICDAR 2023 Workshops, 2023, pp. 83-93. doi: 10.1007/978-3-031-41498-5_6&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="other-publications">Other Publications&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A. Baró, C. Badal, P. Torras, A. Fornés, &lt;strong>“Handwritten Historical Music Recognition through Sequence-to-Sequence with Attention Mechanism”&lt;/strong> in Proceedings of the 3rd International Workshop on Reading Music Systems, 2021, pp. 55-59.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>P. Torras, A. Baró, L. Kang, A. Fornés, &lt;strong>“Improving Handwritten Music Recognition through Language Model Integration”&lt;/strong> in Proceedings of the 4th International Workshop on Reading Music Systems, 2022.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="projects">Projects&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s Thesis: &lt;strong>Integration of Language Models in Sequence to Sequence Optical Music Recognition Systems&lt;/strong>. May be found &lt;a href="https://ddd.uab.cat/pub/tfg/2021/tfg_345965/TFG_informefinal.pdf">here&lt;/a> (awarded a 9.6/10)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Master&amp;rsquo;s Thesis: &lt;strong>Music Tree Notation for End-to-End Optical Music Recognition&lt;/strong>. May be found &lt;a href="https://ptorras.github.io/docs/MasterThesis.pdf">here&lt;/a> (awarded a 10/10)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="awards">Awards&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Extraordinary Academic Achievement Award, B. Sc. in Computer Science (2021)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Best Master&amp;rsquo;s Thesis Award, M. Sc. in Computer Vision (2022)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="studies">Studies&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="academic">Academic&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>B. Sc. in Computer Science by Universitat Autònoma de Barcelona (2021).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>M. Sc. in Computer Vision by Universitat Autònoma de Barcelona, Universitat
Politècnica de Catalunya, Universitat Pompeu Fabra and Universitat Oberta de
Catalunya (2022).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="other">Other&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Federative Chess Instructor Course &amp;ndash; Registered in the Catalan Sport Professionals Registry (ROPEC) with number 039549 (2019)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="experience">Experience&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Chess Instructor at Club Escacs Montmeló (2018 - ongoing)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Intern at Computer Vision Center (Universitat Autònoma de Barcelona) working
in the &lt;a href="https://de-crypt.org/team.php">Decrypt&lt;/a> project
(September 2020 - April 2021).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Intern at the Computer Vision Center (Universitat Autònoma de Barcelona)
working in Optical Music Recognition (June 2021 - October 2021)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills">Skills&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Tools: Python, Pytorch, OpenCV, C/C++, Keras, Numpy, Matlab&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fields: Computer Vision, Optical Music Recognition, Document Analysis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hobbies: Self-taught music theory and piano, 1898 peak FIDE chess rating&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="languages">Languages&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Catalan: Native Level&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spanish: Native Level&lt;/li>
&lt;li>English: Certified C1 Level&lt;/li>
&lt;li>French: Basic Level&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Italian: Basic Level&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="traits">Traits&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Hard-working, quick learner, responsible, creative, organised, enthusiastic.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Inauguration</title><link>https://ptorras.github.io/posts/test/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 21:25:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ptorras.github.io/posts/test/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have finally decided to build my own blog. Not that I expect to be very active,
nor to people to find my writing appealing in any way, shape or form. Nevertheless,
I find it very interesting to have a place where I can lay out my thoughts and
essentially scream into the endless void that is the Internet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s pretty much it for the introductions. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested to know who
I am, do head over to my &lt;a href="https://ptorras.github.io/resume/">about&lt;/a> page. If you want to keep reading,
just scroll around and pick whatever you fancy most.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>